export default {
  id: 'low_1006_5_2a',
  name: '상용한자(5학년-2/음독찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '承', answer: ['이을 승', 'うけたまわ(る)', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '示', answer: ['보일 시', 'しめ(す)', 'じ、し'] },
    { question: '識', answer: ['알 식', '알', 'しき'] },
    { question: '眼', answer: ['눈 안', 'まなこ', 'がん、[げん]'] },
    { question: '圧', answer: ['누를 압', '누를', 'あつ'] },
    { question: '液', answer: ['진 액', '진', 'えき'] },
    { question: '額', answer: ['이마 액', 'ひたい', 'がく'] },
    { question: '桜', answer: ['앵두 앵', 'さくら', 'おう'] },
    { question: '余', answer: ['남을 여', 'あま(る)、あま(す)', 'よ'] },
    { question: '易', answer: ['바꿀 역/쉬울 이', 'やさしい', 'えき、い'] },
    { question: '逆', answer: ['거스릴 역', 'さか、さか(らう)', 'ぎゃく'] },
    { question: '演', answer: ['펼 연', '펼', 'えん'] },
    { question: '燃', answer: ['탈 연', 'も(える)、も(やす)、も(す)', 'ねん'] },
    { question: '永', answer: ['길 영', 'なが(い)', 'えい'] },
    { question: '営', answer: ['경영할 영', 'いとな(む)', 'えい'] },
    { question: '預', answer: ['맡길 예', 'あず(ける)、あず(かる)', 'よ'] },
    { question: '往', answer: ['갈 왕', '갈', 'おう'] },
    { question: '容', answer: ['얼굴 용', '얼굴', 'よう'] },
    { question: '衛', answer: ['지킬 위', '지킬', 'えい'] },
    { question: '恩', answer: ['은혜 은', '은혜', 'おん'] },
    { question: '応', answer: ['응할 응', 'こた(える)', 'おう'] },
    { question: '義', answer: ['옳을 의', '옳을', 'ぎ'] },
    { question: '移', answer: ['옮길 이', 'うつ(る)、うつ(す)', 'い'] },
    { question: '益', answer: ['더할 익', '더할', 'えき、[やく]'] },
    { question: '因', answer: ['인할 인', 'よ(る)', 'いん'] },
    { question: '任', answer: ['맡길 임', 'まか(せる)、まか(す)', 'にん'] },
    { question: '資', answer: ['재물 자', '재물', 'し'] },
    { question: '雑', answer: ['섞일 잡', '섞일', 'ざつ、ぞう'] },
    { question: '張', answer: ['베풀 장', 'は(る)', 'ちょう'] },
    { question: '再', answer: ['두 재', 'ふたた(び)', 'さい、[さ]'] },
    { question: '在', answer: ['있을 재', 'あ(る)', 'ざい'] },
    { question: '財', answer: ['재물 재', '재물', 'ざい、さい'] },
    { question: '災', answer: ['재앙 재', 'わざわ(い)', 'さい'] },
    { question: '敵', answer: ['대적할 적', 'かたき', 'てき'] },
    { question: '績', answer: ['길쌈할 적', '길쌈할', 'せき'] },
    { question: '適', answer: ['맞을 적', '맞을', 'てき'] },
    { question: '銭', answer: ['돈 전', 'ぜに', 'せん'] },
    { question: '絶', answer: ['끊을 절', 'た(える)、た(やす)、た(つ)', 'ぜつ'] },
    { question: '接', answer: ['이을 접', 'つ(ぐ)', 'せつ'] },
    { question: '程', answer: ['한도 정', 'ほど', 'てい'] },
    { question: '情', answer: ['뜻 정', 'なさ(け)', 'じょう、[せい]'] },
    { question: '政', answer: ['정사 정', 'まつりごと', 'せい、[しょう]'] },
    { question: '精', answer: ['정할 정', '정할', 'せい、[しょう]'] },
    { question: '際', answer: ['즈음 제', 'きわ', 'さい'] },
    { question: '制', answer: ['절제할 제', '절제할', 'せい'] },
    { question: '製', answer: ['지을 제', '지을', 'せい'] },
    { question: '提', answer: ['끌 제', 'さ(げる)', 'てい'] },
    { question: '祖', answer: ['할아버지 조', '할아버지', 'そ'] },
    { question: '造', answer: ['지을 조', 'つく(る)', 'ぞう'] },
    { question: '条', answer: ['가지 조', '가지', 'じょう'] },
    { question: '罪', answer: ['허물 죄', 'つみ', 'ざい'] },
    { question: '準', answer: ['준할 준', '준할', 'じゅん'] },
    { question: '増', answer: ['더할 증', 'ま(す)、ふ(える)、ふ(やす)', 'ぞう'] },
    { question: '証', answer: ['증거 증', '증거', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '枝', answer: ['가지 지', 'えだ', 'し'] },
    { question: '志', answer: ['뜻 지', 'こころざ(す)、こころざし', 'し'] },
    { question: '支', answer: ['지탱할 지', 'ささ(える)', 'し'] },
    { question: '職', answer: ['직분 직', '직분', 'しょく'] },
    { question: '織', answer: ['짤 직', 'お(る)', 'しょく、しき'] },
    { question: '質', answer: ['바탕 질', '바탕', 'しつ、しち、[ち]'] },
    { question: '賛', answer: ['도울 찬', '도울', 'さん'] },
    { question: '採', answer: ['캘 채', '캘', 'さい'] },
    { question: '責', answer: ['꾸짖을 책', 'せ(める)', 'せき'] },
    { question: '妻', answer: ['아내 처', 'つま', 'さい'] },
    { question: '招', answer: ['부를 초', 'まね(く)', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '総', answer: ['다 총', '다', 'そう'] },
    { question: '築', answer: ['쌓을 축', 'きず(く)', 'ちく'] },
    { question: '測', answer: ['헤아릴 측', 'はか(る)', 'そく'] },
    { question: '則', answer: ['법칙 칙', '법칙', 'そく'] },
    { question: '快', answer: ['쾌할 쾌', 'こころよ(い)', 'かい'] },
    { question: '態', answer: ['모습 태', '모습', 'たい'] },
    { question: '統', answer: ['거느릴 통', 'す(べる)', 'とう'] },
    { question: '退', answer: ['물러날 퇴', 'しりぞ(く)、しりぞ(ける)', 'たい'] },
    { question: '破', answer: ['깨뜨릴 파', 'やぶ(る)、やぶ(れる)', 'は'] },
    { question: '判', answer: ['판단할 판', '판단할', 'はん、ばん'] },
    { question: '版', answer: ['판목 판', '판목', 'はん'] },
    { question: '編', answer: ['엮을 편', 'あ(む)', 'へん'] },
    { question: '評', answer: ['평할 평', '평할', 'ひょう'] },
    { question: '布', answer: ['베 포', 'ぬの', 'ふ'] },
    { question: '暴', answer: ['사나울 폭', 'あば(れる)、あば(く)', 'ぼう、[ばく]'] },
    { question: '俵', answer: ['나누어 줄 표', 'たわら', 'ひょう'] },
    { question: '豊', answer: ['풍년 풍', 'ゆた(か)', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '河', answer: ['물 하', 'かわ', 'か'] },
    { question: '賀', answer: ['하례할 하', '하례할', 'が'] },
    { question: '限', answer: ['한할 한', 'かぎ(る)', 'げん'] },
    { question: '解', answer: ['풀 해', 'と(く)、と(かす)、と(ける)', 'かい、げ'] },
    { question: '許', answer: ['허락할 허', 'ゆる(す)', 'きょ'] },
    { question: '険', answer: ['험할 험', 'けわ(しい)', 'けん'] },
    { question: '現', answer: ['나타날 현', 'あらわ(れる)、あらわ(す)', 'げん'] },
    { question: '護', answer: ['도울 호', '도울', 'ご'] },
    { question: '混', answer: ['섞을 혼', 'ま(じる)、ま(ざる)、ま(ぜる)、こ(む)', 'こん'] },
    { question: '効', answer: ['본받을 효', 'き(く)', 'こう'] },
    { question: '確', answer: ['굳을 확', 'たし(か)、たし(かめる)', 'かく'] },
    { question: '厚', answer: ['두터울 후', 'あつ(い)', 'こう'] },
    { question: '興', answer: ['일 흥', 'おこ(る)、おこ(す)', 'こう、きょう'] }
  ]
}
